<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Snap Websites Server == e-payment credit card settings page widgets
Copyright (C) 2014-2017  Made to Order Software Corp.

This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify
it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
the Free Software Foundation; either version 2 of the License, or
(at your option) any later version.

This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
GNU General Public License for more details.

You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
along with this program; if not, write to the Free Software
Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin St, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA
-->
<editor-form owner="epayment_creditcard" id="settings" content-modified="2016-03-30 19:18:09">
  <timeout minutes="1440"/> <!-- 1 day -->
  <mode action="edit"/>
  <immediate/>
  <focus refid="show_one_name"/>
  <on-save allow-edit="yes"/>
  <taborder>
    <tabindex refid="show_one_name"/>
    <tabindex refid="show_business_name"/>
    <tabindex refid="show_delivery"/>
    <tabindex refid="show_address2"/>
    <tabindex refid="show_province"/>
    <tabindex refid="show_country"/>
    <tabindex refid="default_country"/>
    <tabindex refid="show_phone"/>
    <tabindex refid="gateway"/>
  </taborder>

  <widget id="editor-session" type="hidden" field="editor::session" path="editor/session">
  </widget>
  <widget id="editor-timeout" type="silent" field="editor::timeout" path="editor/timeout">
  </widget>

  <!-- optional fields -->
  <widget id="show_one_name" type="checkmark" field="epayment_creditcard::show_one_name" path="epayment/credit_card/show_one_name" auto-save="int8">
    <tooltip>When selected (default) the attention fields of the billing and delivery addresses gets hidden.</tooltip>
    <help>When this flag is selected (which is the default), the systems asked for a single user name above the credit card number. Otherwise, the customer can enter a different name in the billing and delivery addresses.</help>
    <label>One customer name for credit card and addresses.</label>
    <value>1</value>
  </widget>
  <widget id="show_business_name" type="checkmark" field="epayment_creditcard::show_business_name" path="epayment/credit_card/show_business_name" auto-save="int8">
    <tooltip>When selected the billing and delivery addresses include a field where the user can enter his business name.</tooltip>
    <help>Check this flag in order to allow the customer to enter a business name in the billing and/or delivery area.</help>
    <label>Show fields to enter a business name.</label>
    <value>1</value>
  </widget>
  <widget id="show_delivery" type="checkmark" field="epayment_creditcard::show_delivery" path="epayment/credit_card/show_delivery" auto-save="int8">
    <tooltip>Select to allow two addresses: Billing address and Delivery address.</tooltip>
    <help>By selecting this flag you allow the user to enter a billing address which is different from the delivery address.</help>
    <label>Show seperate Billing and Delivery addresses.</label>
  </widget>
  <widget id="show_address2" type="checkmark" field="epayment_creditcard::show_address2" path="epayment/credit_card/show_address2" auto-save="int8">
    <tooltip>Uncheck this checkmark if you do not want people to choose to enter a second line for their address.</tooltip>
    <help>In most cases, the more detail the better, however, at times, a second line in the address can prevent a credit card gateway you are using from working right.</help>
    <label>Show the second line in the user's address.</label>
    <value>1</value>
  </widget>
  <widget id="show_province" type="checkmark" field="epayment_creditcard::show_province" path="epayment/credit_card/show_province" auto-save="int8">
    <tooltip>Uncheck this checkmark if you do not want people to enter a province or state name.</tooltip>
    <help>If you expect your users from a country where the province or state is not generally included in their address, then you may hide this field.</help>
    <label>Show the Province / State field.</label>
    <value>1</value>
  </widget>
  <widget id="show_country" type="checkmark" field="epayment_creditcard::show_country" path="epayment/credit_card/show_country" auto-save="int8">
    <tooltip>Uncheck this checkmark if you do not want people to enter the name of their country.</tooltip>
    <help>If your sales are limited to your country, you want to uncheck this checkmark. You may enter the default country name below.</help>
    <label>Show the Country field.</label>
    <value>1</value>
  </widget>
  <widget id="default_country" type="line-edit" field="epayment_creditcard::default_country" path="epayment/credit_card/default_country" no-toolbar="no-toolbar" auto-save="string">
    <tooltip>Enter the name of the default country. (WARNING: if you enter a default, many users are likely to not enter their country name. Be careful.)</tooltip>
    <help>
      In general, you will want to enter the name of the country you
      do business from. The default is to not specify a default. This
      ensures people enter their country name instead of leaving the
      default <em>by mistake.</em>
    </help>
    <sizes>
      <max>64</max>
    </sizes>
    <background-value>default country name</background-value>
  </widget>
  <widget id="show_phone" type="dropdown" field="epayment_creditcard::show_phone" path="epayment/credit_card/show_phone" auto-save="int8">
    <tooltip>Select how the <strong>Phone</strong> field has to be managed: hidden, shown but optional, or required.</tooltip>
    <help>If you are selling items over the internet (i.e. a PDF file) then it may increase your sales by not asking for a phone number. If you are shipping goods, a phone number may actually be required.</help>
    <label>Show the Country field.</label>
    <preset>
      <item value="0">Hide the <strong>Phone</strong> field</item>
      <item value="1" default="default">Show an optional <strong>Phone</strong> field</item>
      <item value="2">Show a required <strong>Phone</strong> field</item>
    </preset>
  </widget>

  <widget id="allow_credit_card_tokens" type="checkmark" field="epayment_creditcard::allow_credit_card_tokens" path="epayment/credit_card/allow_credit_card_tokens" auto-save="int8">
    <tooltip>
      Allow Snap! to register credit card tokens. This will allow
      the system to re-charge a card in case you accept subscriptions.
    </tooltip>
    <help>
      By default the Snap! system allows for subscriptions (repeat charges
      to the same user on a specially scheduled time frame.) By turning off
      this checkmark, you prevent such from happening with credit cards
      (You may still offer services that allow for subscriptions such as
      PayPal.) Such credit card tokens may be considered personal data
      and thus may not be data you want to have on your website.
    </help>
    <label>Allow Snap! to register credit card tokens for subscriptions.</label>
    <value>1</value>
  </widget>
  <widget id="gateway" type="dropdown" field="epayment_creditcard::gateway" path="epayment/credit_card/gateway" auto-save="string">
    <tooltip>Select the default gateway. It is possible to <em>force</em> the use of a credit card gateway by specifying it on the URI, otherwise this one is used.</tooltip>
    <help>In most cases, it is not required to define a default gateway because it will automatically be defined using a query string variable on the URI used to retrieve the user credit card information. However, if you offer multiple gateways, it can become useful to have a default one, just in case.</help>
    <preset>
      <item value="no-default" default="default">No default gateway</item>
    </preset>
  </widget>

</editor-form>
<!-- vim: ts=2 sw=2 et
-->
