<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
  see /usr/share/snapwebsites/xsd/bundles.xsd for details
  to verify your changes (change the == with two dashes):
    xmllint ==noout ==schema /usr/share/snapwebsites/xsd/bundles.xsd /etc/snapwebsites/services.d/bundle-firewall.xml
-->
<bundle>
  <name>firewall</name>
  <description>
    <p>The snapfirewall daemon allows enforcing strong firewall
    rules from any computer in your cluster.</p>

    <p>It should be installed on all systems.</p>

    <p>Note that the firewall requires the snapdbproxy package
    since it makes use of the database to manage the list
    of IP addresses to block.</p>

    <p><strong>IMPORTANT NOTE:</strong> the IP address that
    the VPN generates for your computers are NOT used with the
    firewall because all those IP addresses are virtual and
    they do not interact with the firewall at all. So, in the
    following questions, you do not have to enter any IP
    addresses that your VPN generates.</p>
  </description>
  <fields>
    <field name="public_ip" type="input">
      <label>This Computer Public IP</label>
      <description>Enter the IP address of this computer, the one facing the Internet.</description>
    </field>
    <field name="public_interface" type="input">
      <label>The Interface This Computer uses for Public IP</label>
      <description>Enter the name of the interface (such as 'eth0') that this computer uses for his Public IP address.</description>
    </field>
    <field name="private_ip" type="input">
      <label>This Computer Private IP</label>
      <description>Enter the private IP address of this computer, the one used to communicate with your other private computers.</description>
    </field>
    <field name="private_interface" type="input">
      <label>The Interface This Computer uses for Private IP</label>
      <description>Enter the name of the interface (such as 'eth1') that this computer uses for his Private IP address.</description>
    </field>
    <field name="admin_ips" type="input">
      <label>List of Administrator IPs</label>
      <description>Enter the <strong>space separated</strong> list of IPs that your administrators use to access this computer.</description>
    </field>
    <field name="private_network_ips" type="input">
      <label>Private Network IPs</label>
      <description>Enter the <strong>space separated</strong> list of IPs of all the computers that may access this computer so we can open the corresponding ports in the firewall.</description>
    </field>
    <field name="secure_ip" type="input">
      <label>Secure IP</label>
      <description>Enter the secure IP of this computer if you have one. This is most often the <code>tun0</code> IP address created by OpenVPN. An address such as 10.8.0.34. This field can remain empty if you are not using OpenVPN or if you want to install the firewall before OpenVPN.</description>
    </field>
  </fields>
  <affected-services>snapmanagerdaemon</affected-services>
  <packages>snapfirewall, fail2ban</packages>
  <postinst>
    # Setup the firewall IPs and interfaces.
    # Wed Sep  7 13:16:27 PDT 2016: Now edits firewall.conf, instead of the main firewall script.
    #
    sed -i.bak \
      -e "s/@BUNDLE_PUBLIC_IP@/$BUNDLE_INSTALLATION_PUBLIC_IP/" \
      -e "s/@BUNDLE_PUBLIC_INTERFACE@/$BUNDLE_INSTALLATION_PUBLIC_INTERFACE/" \
      -e "s/@BUNDLE_PRIVATE_IP@/$BUNDLE_INSTALLATION_PRIVATE_IP/" \
      -e "s/@BUNDLE_PRIVATE_INTERFACE@/$BUNDLE_INSTALLATION_PRIVATE_INTERFACE/" \
      -e "s/@BUNDLE_ADMIN_IPS@/$BUNDLE_INSTALLATION_ADMIN_IPS/" \
      -e "s/@BUNDLE_PRIVATE_NETWORK_IPS@/$BUNDLE_INSTALLATION_PRIVATE_NETWORK_IPS/" \
      -e "s/@BUNDLE_SECURE_IP@/$BUNDLE_INSTALLATION_SECURE_IP/" \
            /etc/network/firewall.conf

    # The packager does not install the firewall since it requires
    # those IP addresses and interface names, so we set it up now
    #
    /etc/network/firewall
  </postinst>
</bundle>
<!--
  vim: ts=2 sw=2 et
-->
