<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Snap Websites Server == password blacklist manager page
Copyright (C) 2014-2017  Made to Order Software Corp.

This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify
it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
the Free Software Foundation; either version 2 of the License, or
(at your option) any later version.

This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
GNU General Public License for more details.

You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
along with this program; if not, write to the Free Software
Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin St, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA
-->
<editor-form owner="password" id="blacklist" content-modified="2015-12-22 11:28:10">
  <mode action="edit"/>
  <immediate/>
  <focus refid="check_password"/>
  <on-save allow-edit="yes"/>
  <taborder>
    <tabindex refid="check_password"/>
  </taborder>
  <widget id="editor-session" type="hidden" field="editor::session" path="editor/session">
  </widget>

  <!-- check password -->
  <widget id="check_password" type="line-edit" path="password/check_password" no-toolbar="no-toolbar" auto-save="no">
    <tooltip>Enter a password and click on <strong>Check Password</strong> to know whether it is black listed.</tooltip>
    <help>
      This box lets you enter one password to know whether it is blacklisted
      in this current Snap! Websites installation. Since the database of
      blacklisted password is common to all the websites installed on a
      cluster, only the top website administrator has access to this page.
    </help>
  </widget>

  <!-- upload / add -->
  <widget id="upload" type="dropped-file-with-preview" path="password/upload" no-toolbar="no-toolbar" auto-save="no">
    <tooltip>
      Drag and drop, or use the Browse button, to upload a file of
      passwords. The file must be a list of passwords, one per line.
    </tooltip>
    <help>
      <p>This widgets lets you drag and drop any number of files to quickly
      add passwords to the database. A file must be composed of one
      password per line. A line ends with any number of newline and
      carriage return characters. Empty lines are ignored. We do not
      support any kind of comments since some password may start with
      a '#' character or any other comment line starter.</p>

      <p>We offer one really large password file in the password plugin.
      This file gets installed automatically so you do not have to
      do anything about it.</p>
    </help>
  </widget>
  <widget id="new_passwords" type="text-edit" path="password/new_passwords" no-toolbar="no-toolbar" auto-save="no">
    <tooltip>
      Enter one password per line and then click <strong>Add Passwords</strong>.
      Re-adding the same password multiple times has no specific effects and
      thus it is safe.
    </tooltip>
    <help>
      This widget allows one to quickly add passwords manually without
      having to create a file to upload.
    </help>
  </widget>

  <!-- remove -->
  <widget id="remove_passwords" type="text-edit" path="password/remove_passwords" no-toolbar="no-toolbar" auto-save="no">
    <tooltip>
      You may have your favorite password listed in the password blacklist.
      This option gives you the possibility to remove the password from
      the list. It is, obviously, not recommended to remove any blacklisted
      passwords unless some were added by mistake.
    </tooltip>
    <help>
      This box lets you enter one or more password (one password per line)
      and then click on the <strong>Remove Password</strong> button.
      You should not remove passwords unless, somehow, some were added
      to the blacklist by mistake.
    </help>
  </widget>

</editor-form>
<!-- vim: ts=2 sw=2 et
-->
